Charles G. Hall Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Charles G. Hall Papers.
undated, 1828-1972
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Hall, Charles Gardner, 1889-1969.
2 linear feet.
The Charles G. Hall Papers contain correspondence, diaries, family papers, scrapbooks, photographs, publications, and other papers, relating to Hall's personal life, student days at Connecticut Agricultural College, activities as doorkeeper of Connecticut House of Representatives, state politics, events at University of Connecticut, and family affairs.
MSS19790006
Biography
Charles Gardner Hall was born in 1888 and attended Connecticut Agricultural College. He was the doorkeeper of Connecticut House of Representatives and a farmer living in Mansfield Center, CT. Charles Gardner Hall also served in the House of Representative as a Republican, representing Mansfield for two terms (1947 and 1949). Gardner died in 1969.
Scope and Content
The Charles G. Hall Papers contain correspondence, diaries, family papers, scrapbooks, photographs, publications, and other papers, relating to Hall's personal life, student days at Connecticut Agricultural College, activities as doorkeeper of Connecticut House of Representatives, state politics, events at University of Connecticut, and family affairs.
Arrangement
Series I: Diaries ( 1888-1969 ) consists of fifty-three diaries written by Charles G. Hall and his family members. The entries detail daily occurrences and reports of the weather. Also included in this section is a diary written by Hall's' aunt, Julie Hall Brown, during the year of his birth (1889).
Series II: Personal Papers ( undated, 1828-1972 ) contains correspondence primarily received from Hall's political colleagues. Also included are Hall's General Assembly bills regarding smoking in bed and injuries incurred in state parks and forests (1949), two scrapbooks of newspaper clippings (1914); legal papers and Germaine Hall's composition book (1934)
Series III: Photographs ( undated, 1905-1965 ) contains photographs of Charles G. Hall in various classes and in the dormitory at Connecticut Agricultural College. Other photographs focus on University of Connecticut events and the House of Representatives with Hall as doorkeeper.
Series IV: General Assembly ( 1915-1951 ) consists of two reports by the Claims Committee (1947, 1949) and General Assembly publications which include: Manual and Role of the General Assembly (1915), Calendar for the House of Representatives (1915), an address by the clerk of the House (146), a booklet entitled Information for Connecticut Legislators and a directory of the 1951 General Assembly and elected state officials.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University's history. See especially, University Memorabilia Collection, University Scrapbook Collection, University Photograph Collection, and the papers of Robert F. Belden, A. J. Brundage, James R. Case, Fitts Family, Donald and Margaret Gaylord, Albert C. and Ralph D. Gilbert, Lena Hurlburt, Howard Merrill, Lawrence F. Morico, A. J. Pierpont, Phil Samponaro, August Schulze, Randolph and Beatrice Whaples, and Stanley D. Woodmansee in addition to administrative records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Address by Dwight D. Eisenhower. Dodd Call No.
Addresses by the Honorable Paul G. Hoffman. Dodd Call No.
Almanac. Dodd Call No.
Birds of Storrs and Vicinity. Dodd Call No.
Birth of a Nation. Dodd Call No.
Connecticut Register. Dodd Call No.
Connecticut's Old Houses. Dodd Call No.
Family Fall-Out Shelters. Dodd Call No.
Highlights of the Byrd Antarctica Expedition. Dodd Call No.
Law Making in Connecticut. Dodd Call No.
Old Farmer's Almanac. Dodd Call No.
Outline of Government in Connecticut. Dodd Call No.
Picturesque America. Dodd Call No.
Pierce's Memorandum and Accounting Book. Dodd Call No.
Pocket Manual. Dodd Call No.
State Employees Retirement Act. Dodd Call No.
University of Connecticut materials (president's newsletters, bulletins of Connecticut Agricultural College, and other university and college publications), State of Connecticut publications have been integrated into the periodical collections.
Photographs and postcards have been relocated to the University Photograph Collection. The SCrapbook has been relocated to the University Scrapbook Collection (1979_0006_scpb_1).
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Hall, Charles Gardner, 1889-1969.; Brown, Julie Hall.; Hall, Germaine.
Organizations:
Connecticut Agricultural College.; University of Connecticut.; Connecticut General Assembly.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.); Mansfield Center (Conn.)
Subjects:
Connecticut. General Assembly. House of Representatives.; Connecticut. General Assembly Committees.; Connecticut Agricultural College--Students.; Agriculture--Connecticut.; Universities and colleges--Connecticut.; Agricultural colleges--Connecticut.; Legislation--Connecticut.; Legislative bodies--Connecticut.; Fishery law and legislation--Connecticut.; Birds--Connecticut.; Game laws--Connecticut.; Historic buildings--Connecticut.; Dwellings--Connecticut.; Public institutions--Connecticut.; Connecticut--Education--Universities and colleges.; Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.; Connecticut--Natural resources--Birds.; Storrs (Conn.)--Natural resources--Birds.; Connecticut--Politics and government--1865-1950.; Connecticut--Politics and government--1951-; Connecticut--Agriculture--Farms and farming.; Connecticut--Family and personal papers--19th-20th centuries.; Connecticut--Historic buildings and sites.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Diaries.; Manuscripts.
Occupations:
Farmer.; Public officer.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated in December 1979.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Diaries, 1888-1969
  - 1888-1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944-1958 (Box 2)
  - 1959-1969 (Box 3)
- Series II: Personal Papers, undated, 1828-1972
  - Bill's and Legislative bulletin, 1949 (Box 4:, Folder 1)
  - Composition book (Germaine Hall), 1934 (Box 4:, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1915-1949 (Box 4:, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1972 (Box 4:, Folder 4)
  - Discourse on indecent remarks, 1828 (Box 4:, Folder 5)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1963 (Box 4:, Folder 6)
  - Legal records, 1906, 1910, 1947 (Box 4:, Folder 7)
  - Maps, undated, 1938 (Box 4:, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper articles, 1914, 1941, 1961 (Box 4:, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated, 1836-1837 (Box 4:, Folder 10)
  - War Ration book, 1942 (Box 4:, Folder 11)
- Series III: Photographs, undated, 1905-1965
  - University of Connecticut contest, 1960 (Box 5:, Folder 14)
  - UConn Professors (unidentified), undated (Box 5:, Folder 15)
  - University of Connecticut Varsity Basketball, 1964-1965 (Box 5:, Folder 16)
  - Connecticut Agricultural College/University of Connecticut postcards, undated (Box 5:, Folder 17)
  - C.A.C. Dorm, 1019-1911 (Box 5:, Folder 18)
  - C.A.C. Sheep Husbandry Class, 1911-1912 (Box 5:, Folder 19)
  - C.A.C. Dairy Class, 1910-1911 (Box 5:, Folder 20)
  - Charles Hall - ROTC (photocopy), 1910-1911 (Box 5:, Folder 21)
  - C.A.C. Girls' Basketball Team, 1905 (Box 5:, Folder 22)
  - C.A.C. Students, undated (Box 5:, Folder 23)
  - Connecticut House of Representatives, 1915 (Box OS)
  - Connecticut postcards, undated (Box 5:, Folder 24)
  - Admiral Dewey, undated (Box 5:, Folder 25)
- Series IV: General Assembly, 1915-1951
  - Committee Reports, 1947, 1949 (Box 4:, Folder 12)
  - Publications, 1915, 1947-1949, 1951 (Box 4:, Folder 13)